<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cendaran-ttrpg]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>cendaran-ttrpg</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:58:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:58:49 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute. Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thank you for your interest in playtesting the Cendaran TTRPG! We're looking forward to seeing what sort of trouble you all get yourselves into. These rules will change regularly, but we'll make sure to mention any changes in the Discord!]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:53:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>