<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cendaran-ttrpg]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>cendaran-ttrpg</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:59:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:59:06 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Races.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:56:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thank you for your interest in playtesting the Cendaran TTRPG! We're looking forward to seeing what sort of trouble you all get yourselves into. These rules will change regularly, but we'll make sure to mention any changes in the Discord!]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:53:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>