<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cendaran-ttrpg]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>cendaran-ttrpg</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:04:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:04:34 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Fire Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fire Magic specializes in raw damage, and is surprisingly decent with healing, but lacks powerful defensive spells and doesn't have very many utility spells. Optional Flavor: Fire Magic can be cast as Lightning, as well. This makes no changes to how the spells behave. These are in no particular order at the moment.Statblocks Firebolt/Lightning Bolt: (1AP) - Fire a single bolt at an enemy within range. Burning Laser/Tesla Coil: (Channeled: 2AP startup/1AP upkeep) - Channel a beam at an enemy within range. Cannot move or regenerate AP while the channel is active. Burning Touch/Shocking Touch: (1AP) - Make a melee attack against an enemy you can reach. Soothing Heat: A warm, painless flame closes recent wounds.
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional fire damage.
]]></description><link>spells/fire-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Spells/Fire Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:03:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Magic Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you create your character, you'll choose which elemental affinity they have. If you're a caster, this determines which element your character will have proficiency in casting. While it's possible to cast outside of your element, doing so is more difficult than sticking with your affinity. There are pros and cons to consider, whether you specialize in your element or decide to pick up a few spells outside of it. Spells are distributed between Assault and Support categories. Inside each category, spells are further distributed between ranks. So for example, a basic attack spell will be Assault, Rank 1. Classes gain access to these groups of spells at different paces! Check your class guide for more info (coming soon.)Each time you level up, you can choose to learn a spell (or technique, covered elsewhere in this manual) which you qualify for. Once a spell is 'learned,' you do not need to make a save to see if the spell is successfully cast. However, you can choose to attempt to cast a spell you don't currently have mastered (provided it's within a rank you have access to), but that you know about. This requires a save, with bonuses or penalties depending on the spell, its difficulty, and your knowledge of it. Additionally, remember to apply a -1 die penalty if the spell is not inside of your elemental affinity. The caster can also spend AP to add additional die to this roll, in order to simulate dumping extra mana into its cast to stabilize the spell. The AP must be used on the initial roll and cannot be used to pad a failed roll after the fact. On a failed spell cast, the caster suffers magical backlash. Even spells intended to have beneficial effects (like healing or shields) may explode or have other unintended effects if the spell fails. Some spells may have special failure effects; check individual spells to see if they list this. <img alt="failed.jpg" src="failed.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>spells/01-magic-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Spells/01 - Magic Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:48:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="failed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="failed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[failed]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="failed.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>failed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">failed.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:45:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="failed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="failed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Stats]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stats determine what your character is good at, on a very basic level. Each stat gives you either passive perks, new actions, or additional die to use for skills that use that stat.Agility determines your turn order in combat, damage with ranged weapons, and can help recover AP faster.Social determines how well you can communicate with others, and your ability to haggle with merchants.Spirit determines how much damage you do with Ki-based attacks, and also your ability to sense and contact spirits.Stamina helps determine your HP and your AP cap.Strength determines how much damage you do with physical melee weapons, unarmed combat, and what kind of melee weapons you can wield. It also determines how much your character can lift, whether it's moving a large object out of the way or picking up another character.Wisdom determines how much damage you do with magic, how much damage your magical defense can absorb, and how easily you can attempt unlearned spells.]]></description><link>getting-started/01-stats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/01 - Stats.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:09:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 - Classes]]></title><description><![CDATA[As an Adventurer, your 'class' determines what you prefer to focus on. Many abilities can be used by multiple classes, but certain classes specialize in certain things. A class learns their favored abilities sooner, and perform them better than other classes. ]]></description><link>getting-started/02-classes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/02 - Classes.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 22:10:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03 - Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute.
Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>getting-started/03-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/03 - Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:06:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute. Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thank you for your interest in playtesting the Cendaran TTRPG! We're looking forward to seeing what sort of trouble you all get yourselves into. These rules will change regularly, but we'll make sure to mention any changes in the Discord!]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:53:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>