<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[cendaran-ttrpg]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>cendaran-ttrpg</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:59:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:59:30 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Ki Skill Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ki Skills are similar to magic, but rely on the SPI stat instead of WIS. They also never require a focus, and can be used by anyone who has a mortal soul. That said, Dolls and Divine Beings don't have ki to use. Their effects are generally less potent than magic.A normal attack that penetrates your opponent's defenses. Deals damage equal to your standard defense die, but when your opponent rolls for defense, discard one of their dice.
Overcharge: For each additional AP spent, discard an additional die. Strike forward with your weapon, creating a shockwave with your ki. Deals normal weapon damage to up to 3 additional targets within 10 feet of your target. Grant yourself or an ally you can touch a temporary resistance to a magical damage type of your choice.]]></description><link>05-ki-skills/01-ki-skill-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">05 - Ki Skills/01 - Ki Skill Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:58:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Perks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Perks are bonuses that change how your character might be roleplayed, or give small bonuses to certain kinds of actions. You pick one on character creation, then pick one on every fourth level. Some have prerequisites that must be met before you can pick them, but many can be chosen by any character. You know how to get on someone's good side without laying it on too thick. You gain +1 die towards any SOC rolls regarding persuading or bluffing.Something about your body just shrugs off toxins. You gain +1 die towards resisting Poison effects.You're less likely to panic or lose your cool than the others, and can keep your composure even in the most dire circumstances.Gain +1 die to resist Fear and Charm effectsYou have an eye for the unusual, and are better able to pick out what doesn't belong... even in places you've never been to before. You gain +1 die to WIS rolls when investigating an area, spotting traps, or in general detecting other things that don't belong. You're not sure why. You've just always felt lucky. Once per day, re-roll a failed roll.A Latent psychic is someone who has psychic potential, but has never trained their psychic ability. They often get a "gut feeling" about dangerous people, get a sense when someone is lying to them, and sometimes peers into real situations when dreaming. Anyone can be born with latent psychic potential, but most never learn about or train this ability. Your GM will make a judgement call on when your psychic ability detects something out of the ordinary. You can attempt to focus your psychic power to forcibly attempt it to detect something, as well. Your GM will decide whether or not you need to roll (WIS) in order to succeed. Your WIS roll is compared to the WIS roll of whoever you are attempting to read.Prerequisite: Psychic (Latent)
Level 1 psychics have learned about and honed their ability. You're beginning to hear "psychic noise." While the noise contains no actual words of peoples' thoughts, it clues you in to their emotions. Additionally, your ability to control your power has increased.You gain +1 die towards WIS rolls that attempt to use your psychic power. In addition to lies and dangerous motives, you can also get a basic feel for a target's emotions. This feeling is vague and may not entirely expose an individual's motives, but may provide a valuable clue. You're good at sneaking around, or even just looking like you belong.You gain +1 die towards any AGI rolls regarding stealth or sleight of hand.]]></description><link>01-getting-started/perks.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/Perks.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:45:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Earth Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Earth specializes in defense and healing. It has reasonable crowd control, but doesn't have many debuffs. Its offensive potential is about average. Earth spells come in either Rock or Plant varietiesThese are called Rumbling ArtsStatblocks Stone Spear/Thorn Shot (+1AP) - Fire a single spear at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Rock the Earth: - Stagger enemies within a zone you designate within range
Earth's Grasp: - Entangle an enemy within range Stone Wall: Creates a defensive wall in an area you designate which absorbs x damage before breaking
Terra's Touch: Heal light wounds on a target you can touch
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional Earth damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/earth-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Earth Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:41:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fire Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fire Magic specializes in raw damage, and is surprisingly decent with healing, but lacks powerful defensive spells and doesn't have very many utility spells. Optional Flavor: Fire Magic can be cast as Lightning, as well. This makes no changes to how the spells behave. These are called Burning ArtsStatblocks Firebolt/Lightning Bolt: (+1AP) - Fire a single bolt at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Burning Laser/Tesla Coil: (Channeled: 2AP startup/1AP upkeep) - Channel a beam at an enemy within range. Cannot move or regenerate AP while the channel is active. Burning Touch/Shocking Touch: (1AP) - Make a melee attack against an enemy you can reach. Soothing Heat: A warm, painless flame closes recent wounds.
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional fire damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/fire-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Fire Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:41:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Light Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Light specializes in healing and support. It has a good amount of utility spells, but doesn't have many direct damage abilities.These are called Blinding ArtsStatblocks Luminous Bolt (+1AP) - Fire a single spear at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Flash: - Disorients enemies within a zone Healing Light: Heals light wounds at range
Barrier: Creates a wall of light that absorbs a certain amount of damage before it breaks.
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional Light damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/light-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Light Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:41:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shadow Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shadow specializes in dealing damage and harassing enemies. It doesn't have much healing, but has a decent amount of utility. These are called Veiling ArtsStatblocks Shadow Needle (+1AP) - Fire a single spear at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Toxic Mist: - Applies poison to enemies within a zone Enshroud: Partially hides an ally, granting them +1 defense die for the duration
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional Shadow damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/shadow-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Shadow Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:41:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Water Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Water specializes in slowing enemies and supporting allies. It's surprisingly weak with healing. Water spells come in either Water or Ice forms.These are called Flowing ArtsStatblocks Aqua Jet/Ice Lance (+1AP) - Fire a single projectile at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Deluge: - Reduces the AGI of enemies within a zone Purify: Removes a poison effect from an ally
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional Water damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/water-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Water Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:41:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wind Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Wind spells specialize in disorienting opponents and buffing allies. It lacks serious defense, but has reasonable offense. Prefers to be at range. Wind comes in either Wind or Sound formsThese are called Howling ArtsStatblocks Windblade/Sonic Blast (+1AP) - Fire a single projectile at an enemy within range, dealing +2d damage.
Overcharge: Spend AP, get +1d per AP spent. Gain no AP.
Airburst: (1AP) - Knocks back an enemy who is within melee range Wind's Grace: Buffs an ally's AGI for 5 rounds
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional wind damage.
]]></description><link>03-magic/wind-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/Wind Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:40:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Combat Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[As you adventure through the various wilds and ruins of the recovering post-apocalypse, you are very likely to encounter some manner of hostile creature or greedy raider. While peaceful options exist, having to defend yourself is inevitable. Before combat begins in earnest, the order of turns made must be determined. This is done by using the AGI stat: the highest AGI character goes first, second highest goes second, etc. In the event of a tie, each character rolls one die to break the tie. In the event of an ambush, the ambushing party takes their turn first on the first round. Afterwards, normal turn order is determined. At the start of your turn, you replenish your AP: Action Points. Action Points are a resource that allow you to attack and defend in a variety of ways. By default you gain 1AP at the start of each round, up to a maximum of 5. There are ways to increase these amounts.Afterward, you can choose to move in addition to one other command.You move along the combat grid an amount equal to or less than your movement speed. Your speed is determined by your race, plus any movement bonuses from AGI or equipment. You attack with an equipped weapon (or barehanded) against a target that's within range, gaining 1 AP by doing so.The attacker and defender both roll a number of d6s, determined by the following:Attacker:STR *OR* AGI(Determined by weapon type) + Weapon Dice Value + Weapon Perks
Defender:STA *OR* AGI(Chosen by defender) + Armor Dice Value + Resistences
Additionally, both attacker and defender may spend AP to boost their roll, at the rate of 1AP per die. This must be done with the initial roll, and cannot be done after the dice have been thrown to change the result. You do not gain AP from the attack if you choose to do this.The attacker and defender then pair their dice off. If the defender has more higher dice than the attacker, they successfully dodge or resist the attack. Otherwise, they take damage equal to the number of higher dice the attacker has. You cast a spell, spending or gaining AP while doing so (see individual spells for AP costs or benefits.) When attacking with magic, the rolls are similar to when attacking with a weapon, but the stats used are different.Attacking:Base Spell Value + WIS + perks
Defending: Base Armor Value + WIS *OR* AGI + resistances See individual Support spells for how their effects are determined.You use an item out of your inventory. This costs no AP. You do nothing else this turn, and brace yourself. Defending in this manner doesn't cost AP, but prevents the AP replenishment step on your next turn. Adds one general defense die until your next turn (some perks may boost this). Some encounters may have objects that can be interacted with, such as levers or doors. Interacting with them usually will not require any kind of dice roll and don't by default use AP, but your DM may make special rules depending on the scenario. ]]></description><link>02-combat/01-combat-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 - Combat/01 - Combat Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:36:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 - Foci]]></title><description><![CDATA[While there are many natural spell-casters in the world, most people need to use a focus in order to use magic. This most notably applies to humans, but other races may have limited magical capabilities, as well. Foci are small magitech devices that enable spellcasting, usually taking the form of a bracer (but other shapes exist, as well.) They're programmed with a pre-set arrangement of spells, and can only ever use those spells.Basically: Natural spell-casters can use any spell they learn from the moment they learn it. But focus-users are limited to whatever spells are programmed into their focus. Like other casters, focus-user can attempt to cast spells available to their focus that they haven't properly 'learned' yet, with the same mechanics. However, unlike a natural caster, if a focus-user switches to a focus that doesn't have access to a learned spell, they can no longer cast that spell. On the other hand, Foci offer a decent amount of flexibility to a caster: a natural-born spell caster with Fire affinity can only ever cast Fire spells. But a focus-user can cast spells of any element, though with a -1 die penalty for non-affinity elements and a -2 penalty for their opposing element. Ordinarily, changing a focus out would be a lengthy process (a full turn in combat), but special Modular Foci allow for changing the elemental crystal in the focus quickly, at the cost of 2AP.]]></description><link>03-magic/02-foci.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/02 - Foci.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:46:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Status Effects]]></title><description><![CDATA[Many spells and skills can cause a Status Effect if it finds purchase on its target. These can range from reducing effectiveness in battle (such as with blind) to dealing damage over time (such as with bleed). Here is listed the status effects and how they work:When a target is stuck by an attack that causes bleed, a number of bleed tokens are placed on that opponent. Each time a bleeding combatant's turn starts, remove one bleed token and deal 1 damage. Bleed tokens can be removed by restoring the afflicted's HP to full by any means. When Blinded, the afflicted suffers a -1 die penalty on attack and dodge rolls. The effect lasts until the start of the next turn, or until a special spell or item is used to remove it. When Charmed, the afflicted will follow basic commands from that which charmed them. The Charmed target can attempt to break out of the Charm each turn with a SOC check, otherwise the effect lasts for 3 turns. An Entangled target can't move. They can break free with a STR save, or with the aid of an ally to attack the bindings. A target who is Afraid suffers a 1 die penalty on all attack and defense rolls. Poison works similarly to Bleed, in that tokens are placed on the target on a successful attack. However, when it comes to removing the poison token, the afflicted can roll a STA save. If successful, the poison token is removed and no damage is delt. If failed, it deals one damage. Poison can only be removed by special spells or items. A Staggered target has their defense rolls reduced by 1 for one turn]]></description><link>01-getting-started/status-effects.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/Status Effects.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:14:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03 - Classes]]></title><description><![CDATA[As an Adventurer, your 'class' determines what you prefer to focus on. Many abilities can be used by multiple classes, but certain classes specialize in certain things. A class learns their favored abilities sooner, and perform them better than other classes. Perhaps you weren't able to learn magic. Perhaps you just weren't any good at it. Perhaps you just prefer the rush of being the first into battle and smashing your enemies with your bare fists. Or a giant hammer. You are a Brute.Brutes lack magic, but make up for it with sheer strength of both body and mind. They can easily wield heavy weapons others struggle with and endure large amounts of damage without breaking a sweat. While they excel in soaking up damage and directing attention to themselves, they can deal punishing blows to enemies unfortunate enough to get within range of their attacks. With some practice, they can even learn some Ki techniques. Brutes may Charge Into Battle! by expending one AP. This command allows the Brute to move an additional 50%, rounded up, but only if they follow it up with a melee attack, which requires its usual AP cost. You cannot use this command and Move on the same turn. You've always had an easy time with magic. Whether you wield it naturally, or learned how to use a focus at a young age, magic was practically second nature to you. When cantrips became as easy as waving your hand, you moved on to learning the more complicated Arts. You are a Mage.Mages specialize in bombarding opponents with potent offensive magic from afar. They learn combat magic faster than anyone else, and get access to the most powerful damage-dealing spells. However, they're quite vulnerable up close.They can learn support magic, but do so slower than Priests and get no bonuses towards it. Their non-magical combat capabilities are also pretty limited. Mages may Ready Spell by spending the normal amount of AP on a spell, but not actually casting it yet. They can then cast the spell on a later turn for free. They can regenerate AP as normal while a spell is readied, but they cannot cast another spell until the readied spell is cast. A readied spell cannot be canceled. It must be cast. You've trained in martial arts, becoming quite familiar with tackling enemies much better-armed than you. Through hard work and dedication, you've begun to incorporate magic and ki into your strikes, allowing you to bypass armor and and deflect blows without your own. You are a Monk.Monks are, in a sense, melee-range casters. Though they are formidable even without magic, they really shine when they can enchant their blows. They focus on direct damage, but can pick up the odd ranged attack or support magic here and there as well. They can dodge or deflect incoming attacks reasonably well, but a direct hit will put them down faster than it would a Brute or a Fighter. Spend 1 AP. Channel any element you have access to into your strike, causing the strike to deal damage as if it were a spell of that element. Use WIS as your damage modifier. You've dedicated yourself to Terra. Maybe you want to protect Her. Maybe you just want to protect Her children. Or maybe you just want to offer a helping hand to those in need. No matter the case, you've dedicated yourself to learning magic. The kind that can heal and protect. You are a Priest.Priests specialize in aiding allies and hindering foes; they learn support magic faster than anyone else. They can shield, heal, and buff allies ... and throw various ailments at their attackers. They can be quite adept at keeping themselves alive... but have much lower damage potential.Spend 1 AP. Choose one damage source type (Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, Light, Shadow, Blunt, Piercing, or Slashing) and grant a friendly target +1 resistance against that damage source. The effect lasts for 5 turns. Only one target can benefit from this effect at a time. You're used to doing whatever is necessary to get the job done. Even when you have good intentions, you like to keep an ace up your sleeve... just in case. Maybe you were forced to fight for scraps to survive when you were younger. Or maybe you just noticed that nice guys finish last. Whatever the case, you're not afraid to play a little dirty. You are a Rogue.Rogues specialize in taking advantage of distractions and playing dirty to disrupt their opponents. They prefer to remain out of sight until the opportunity to strike presents itself, and aren't against using their magic to make this easier. Though they have a bad rep, rogues are just as often good as they are bad. If your opponent is currently distracted, or otherwise unaware of your presence, you gain +1 additional die on an attack against them, without expending any additional AP. You've always had something of a sixth sense. It may have been scary, at first, seeing and hearing people others never noticed... but you soon came to realize that the spirits of the recently deceased are nothing to be afraid of. You decided they needed guidance just like anyone else. You are a Shaman.Shamans excel more than anyone else in using their Ki to protect themselves and others. They train their spiritual affinity to commune with spirits, both to aid the spirits and those still living. Spirits often provide guidance to those willing to lend an ear to their own regrets. While Shamans can, and often do, learn magic, they're strongest when relying on their own spirit. Some Shamans may even find a spiritual traveling companion to act as a long-term guide, in return for helping this companion find peace and to return to Mother Terra. Shamans may Focus for a turn in order to gain an additional AP on the next. Doing so leaves them vulnerable, reducing their passive defense by one die until their next turn. While out of combat, Shamans may attempt to commune with nearby spirits by performing a simple ritual and meditating. Make a Spirit roll to see if you're able to reach any (the GM determines a successful score.) If you have a Spirit Companion, you may contact them, instead, without requiring a ritual (or a roll.) The Shaman may ask the spirit a few questions, but the spirit's helpfulness is entirely up to the GM. ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/03-classes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/03 - Classes.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:20:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 - Stats]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stats determine what your character is good at, on a very basic level. Each stat gives you either passive perks, new actions, or additional die to use for skills that use that stat.Agility determines your turn order in combat, damage with ranged weapons, and can help recover AP faster.Social determines how well you can communicate with others, and your ability to haggle with merchants.Spirit determines how much damage you do with Ki-based attacks, and also your ability to sense and contact spirits.Stamina helps determine your HP and your AP cap.Strength determines how much damage you do with physical melee weapons, unarmed combat, and what kind of melee weapons you can wield. It also determines how much your character can lift, whether it's moving a large object out of the way or picking up another character.Wisdom determines how much damage you do with magic, how much damage your magical defense can absorb, and how easily you can attempt unlearned spells.]]></description><link>01-getting-started/02-stats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/02 - Stats.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 22:58:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Weapon Skill Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[With each level up, a player can choose to learn a new ability that they qualify for. Weapon Skills are among the abilities that can be learned. Weapon Skills grant players who like to rely more on physical combat a choice in how they want to specialize their character. Different weapons have different strengths and weaknesses! Some Weapon Skills are Active Abilities that can be used in a manner similar to Magic, while others are passive perks that make your favored weapon more effective. Proposed weapon types:
Light weapons (Daggers, fists)
Medium Weapons (Swords, hand axes)
Heavy weapons (Greataxes, Giant Hammers)
Reach Weapons (Spears, Whips)
Ranged weapons (Bows, guns)
At level 3, and every 3 levels after (3, 6, 9, etc), you can choose a weapon type to gain additional proficiency in. Each rank of proficiency adds an extra bonus when you make a standard attack with that weapon type. You automatically gain the first proficiency skill with your class (which adds +1 die to your attacks with that weapon). You can choose to 'favor' a weapon that isn't favored by default by your class. So for example, rogues start with proficiency 1 with daggers since they're their class's favored weapon. When they reach level 3, they can choose to favor a new weapon by ranking that weapon's proficiency to 1, instead of leveling dagger proficiency to 2. Daggers are fast-striking weapons that specialize in multi-attacks and causing status effects. They're most commonly wielded by rogues, but monks and fighters can use them well, too. Daggers deal +2 damage dice. Favored Weapons gain +1 die to attack rolls.If you roll a 6 on your standard attack, make a second attack attempt (whether the initial attack hits or not). This can only occur once per turn. By exploiting small gaps in the enemy's defenses, you impose a -1 die penalty on their STA defense rolls. Multi-Attack can now trigger twice in one turn. Deal a quick strike that causes bleeding. If the attack hits, place 3 bleed tokens on the target. Only usable immediately after successfully dodging an attack. Attempt a standard attack against the attacker, provided they're within range to do so. Can only occur once per round. Roll your AGI against a target in melee range. If you succeed, you perform a feint that distracts them, reducing their defense dice by 1 until your next turn. ]]></description><link>04-weapon-skills/01-weapon-skill-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 - Weapon Skills/01 - Weapon Skill Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 18:33:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Leveling Up]]></title><description><![CDATA[With every level up, you add one to a stat of your choice, learn a new skill (whether magic, a weapon skill, or a ki skill) and gain HP (according to your STA bonus). Additionally, you can increase your weapon proficiency every 3 levels.Each class gains access to magics and ki skills at different rates, so check your class's individual tables to see what's available to you! ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/leveling-up.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/Leveling Up.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:19:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[04 - Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute.
Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Harpies are monsters resembling a human with bird wings. They typically live in flocks, but are sometimes seen venturing out on their own. They have a reputation for stealing and troublemaking. &gt;**Flight:** You can fly just as easily as you can walk or run. Natural Magic: Harpies can cast magic without a focus, so long as they align with their affinity. They still need to learn spells in order to use them. Natural Weapons: Harpies can attack with their talons, able to do damage as if they were equipped with a light slashing weapon. You always have favor with these attacks. No Hands: You lack hands. You can't equip weapons or tools that require them. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. Statblocks Nobody is quite sure what spawned Mimics, whether they're a natural Monster of Terra, or if they're some manner of flesh-beast. Mimics specialize in copying the appearances of things they've seen, and are known for hoarding treasure and having an appetite. Mimic: Choose a person or object less than 6 feet in any direction in size, whose shape you have either memorized or can study. Assume that shape. If the shape is an object, you cannot move while using its shape. The shape change isn't perfect, but passersby won't generally notice the imperfections.
Someone who is close enough to inspect you may notice your deception by succeeding a WIS roll against yours. Natural Weapons: By changing the shape of your hands, you may attack as if you were wielding a slashing or piercing light weapon. You always have favor with these attacks. Statblocks Ogres are an old-world Monster known for their size, strength, and love of battle. Ogres are a generally honorable race, and often hold positions as shamans and Monster Clan leaders. Ungifted: Ogres can't use magic without a focus... and generally prefer not to use magic, anyway. Iron Hide: When using STA to roll for defense, take a +1 bonus die. Ogre-Shark: Though typically seen near coastal towns, they can be occasionally spotted just about anywhere. Ogre-Sharks are a little smaller than most other Ogre varieties, and tend to be more laid-back. They still enjoy combat, and especially love showing off their strength.
Ogre-Sharks are usually either Earth or Water attribute. ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/04-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/04 - Races.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 22:10:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - The Game]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the Cendaran TTRPG system, players will operate as a group of Adventurers working with the Adventurer's Guild. Adventurers work tirelessly to keep their communities safe by taking jobs from the guild or following their own leads. They'll do anything from investigating strange locations to defending villages against raiders. As an Adventurer, you'll work alongside your Handler and fellow partymembers to take jobs, earn money and reputation, upgrade your base of operations, and work with the townsfolk to keep things safe. ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/01-the-game.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/01 - The Game.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 20:47:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 - Classes]]></title><description><![CDATA[As an Adventurer, your 'class' determines what you prefer to focus on. Many abilities can be used by multiple classes, but certain classes specialize in certain things. A class learns their favored abilities sooner, and perform them better than other classes. Perhaps you weren't able to learn magic. Perhaps you just weren't any good at it. Perhaps you just prefer the rush of being the first into battle and smashing your enemies with your bare fists. Or a giant hammer. You are a Brute.Brutes lack magic, but make up for it with sheer strength of both body and mind. They can easily wield heavy weapons others struggle with and endure large amounts of damage without breaking a sweat. While they excel in soaking up damage and directing attention to themselves, they can deal punishing blows to enemies unfortunate enough to get within range of their attacks. With some practice, they can even learn some Ki techniques. Brutes may Charge Into Battle! by expending one AP. This command allows the Brute to move an additional 50%, rounded up, but only if they follow it up with a melee attack, which requires its usual AP cost. You cannot use this command and Move on the same turn. Brutes may use their imposing stature to attempt to brag, show off, or intimidate in order to impress or scare a person they're attempting to convince of something. Tell your GM how you intend to do this, and they'll make a judgement call on whether your display gives you +1, -1, or no change in Social dice on your attempt. You've always had something of a sixth sense. It may have been scary, at first, seeing and hearing people others never noticed... but you soon came to realize that the spirits of the recently deceased are nothing to be afraid of. You decided they needed guidance just like anyone else. You are a Shaman.Shamans excel more than anyone else in using their Ki to protect themselves and others. They train their spiritual affinity to commune with spirits, both to aid the spirits and those still living. Spirits often provide guidance to those willing to lend an ear to their own regrets. While Shamans can, and often do, learn magic, they're strongest when relying on their own spirit. Some Shamans may even find a spiritual traveling companion to act as a long-term guide, in return for helping this companion find peace and to return to Mother Terra. Shamans may Meditate for a turn in order to gain an additional AP on the next. Doing so leaves them vulnerable, reducing their passive defense by one die until their next turn. While out of combat, Shamans may attempt to commune with nearby spirits by performing a simple ritual and meditating. Make a Spirit roll to see if you're able to reach any (the GM determines a successful score.) If you have a Spirit Companion, you may contact them, instead, without requiring a ritual (or a roll.) The Shaman may ask the spirit a few questions, but the spirit's helpfulness is entirely up to the GM. ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/02-classes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/02 - Classes.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:40:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Magic Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you create your character, you'll choose which elemental affinity they have. If you're a caster, this determines which element your character will have proficiency in casting. While it's possible to cast outside of your element, doing so is more difficult than sticking with your affinity. There are pros and cons to consider, whether you specialize in your element or decide to pick up a few spells outside of it. Spells are distributed between Assault and Support categories. Inside each category, spells are further distributed between ranks. So for example, a basic attack spell will be Assault, Rank 1. Classes gain access to these groups of spells at different paces! Check your class guide for more info (coming soon.)Each time you level up, you can choose to learn a spell (or technique, covered elsewhere in this manual) which you qualify for. Once a spell is 'learned,' you do not need to make a save to see if the spell is successfully cast. However, you can choose to attempt to cast a spell you don't currently have mastered (provided it's within a rank you have access to), but that you know about. This requires a save, with bonuses or penalties depending on the spell, its difficulty, and your knowledge of it. Additionally, remember to apply a -1 die penalty if the spell is not inside of your elemental affinity. The caster can also spend AP to add additional die to this roll, in order to simulate dumping extra mana into its cast to stabilize the spell. The AP must be used on the initial roll and cannot be used to pad a failed roll after the fact. On a failed spell cast, the caster suffers magical backlash. Even spells intended to have beneficial effects (like healing or shields) may explode or have other unintended effects if the spell fails. Some spells may have special failure effects; check individual spells to see if they list this. <img alt="failed.jpg" src="failed.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-magic/01-magic-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 - Magic/01 - Magic Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:48:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="failed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="failed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Stats]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stats determine what your character is good at, on a very basic level. Each stat gives you either passive perks, new actions, or additional die to use for skills that use that stat.Agility determines your turn order in combat, damage with ranged weapons, and can help recover AP faster.Social determines how well you can communicate with others, and your ability to haggle with merchants.Spirit determines how much damage you do with Ki-based attacks, and also your ability to sense and contact spirits.Stamina helps determine your HP and your AP cap.Strength determines how much damage you do with physical melee weapons, unarmed combat, and what kind of melee weapons you can wield. It also determines how much your character can lift, whether it's moving a large object out of the way or picking up another character.Wisdom determines how much damage you do with magic, how much damage your magical defense can absorb, and how easily you can attempt unlearned spells.]]></description><link>01-getting-started/01-stats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/01 - Stats.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:09:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03 - Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute.
Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>01-getting-started/03-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 - Getting Started/03 - Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:06:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fire Spells]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fire Magic specializes in raw damage, and is surprisingly decent with healing, but lacks powerful defensive spells and doesn't have very many utility spells. Optional Flavor: Fire Magic can be cast as Lightning, as well. This makes no changes to how the spells behave. These are in no particular order at the moment.Statblocks Firebolt/Lightning Bolt: (1AP) - Fire a single bolt at an enemy within range. Burning Laser/Tesla Coil: (Channeled: 2AP startup/1AP upkeep) - Channel a beam at an enemy within range. Cannot move or regenerate AP while the channel is active. Burning Touch/Shocking Touch: (1AP) - Make a melee attack against an enemy you can reach. Soothing Heat: A warm, painless flame closes recent wounds.
Enchant Strikes: Enchant your or an ally's weapon to deal additional fire damage.
]]></description><link>spells/fire-spells.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Spells/Fire Spells.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:03:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Magic Basics]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you create your character, you'll choose which elemental affinity they have. If you're a caster, this determines which element your character will have proficiency in casting. While it's possible to cast outside of your element, doing so is more difficult than sticking with your affinity. There are pros and cons to consider, whether you specialize in your element or decide to pick up a few spells outside of it. Spells are distributed between Assault and Support categories. Inside each category, spells are further distributed between ranks. So for example, a basic attack spell will be Assault, Rank 1. Classes gain access to these groups of spells at different paces! Check your class guide for more info (coming soon.)Each time you level up, you can choose to learn a spell (or technique, covered elsewhere in this manual) which you qualify for. Once a spell is 'learned,' you do not need to make a save to see if the spell is successfully cast. However, you can choose to attempt to cast a spell you don't currently have mastered (provided it's within a rank you have access to), but that you know about. This requires a save, with bonuses or penalties depending on the spell, its difficulty, and your knowledge of it. Additionally, remember to apply a -1 die penalty if the spell is not inside of your elemental affinity. The caster can also spend AP to add additional die to this roll, in order to simulate dumping extra mana into its cast to stabilize the spell. The AP must be used on the initial roll and cannot be used to pad a failed roll after the fact. On a failed spell cast, the caster suffers magical backlash. Even spells intended to have beneficial effects (like healing or shields) may explode or have other unintended effects if the spell fails. Some spells may have special failure effects; check individual spells to see if they list this. <img alt="failed.jpg" src="failed.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>spells/01-magic-basics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Spells/01 - Magic Basics.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:48:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="failed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="failed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[failed]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="failed.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>failed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">failed.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:45:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="failed.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="failed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 - Stats]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stats determine what your character is good at, on a very basic level. Each stat gives you either passive perks, new actions, or additional die to use for skills that use that stat.Agility determines your turn order in combat, damage with ranged weapons, and can help recover AP faster.Social determines how well you can communicate with others, and your ability to haggle with merchants.Spirit determines how much damage you do with Ki-based attacks, and also your ability to sense and contact spirits.Stamina helps determine your HP and your AP cap.Strength determines how much damage you do with physical melee weapons, unarmed combat, and what kind of melee weapons you can wield. It also determines how much your character can lift, whether it's moving a large object out of the way or picking up another character.Wisdom determines how much damage you do with magic, how much damage your magical defense can absorb, and how easily you can attempt unlearned spells.]]></description><link>getting-started/01-stats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/01 - Stats.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:09:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 - Classes]]></title><description><![CDATA[As an Adventurer, your 'class' determines what you prefer to focus on. Many abilities can be used by multiple classes, but certain classes specialize in certain things. A class learns their favored abilities sooner, and perform them better than other classes. ]]></description><link>getting-started/02-classes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/02 - Classes.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 22:10:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[03 - Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute.
Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>getting-started/03-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Getting Started/03 - Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:06:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Races]]></title><description><![CDATA[Statblocks Elves are long-lived, and generally more reclusive. Some live in cities, but many live in their own villages where they hide away from prying eyes. They often see themselves as better than other races, whether they're friendly with them or not. Natural Magic: Elves are capable of naturally using magic from their affinity. They need to learn spells in order to use them, but don't rely on a focus or other external power to do so.
Ageless: Elves don't age past adulthood. They can still be killed by normal means, they simply do not seem to die of old age. Dark Elf: The most reclusive of the elf races, Dark Elves live in dense mountain forests away from other settlements. They're the most distrustful of outsiders among the elves, and are particularly harsh against monsters. Even so, Dark Elves are sometimes spotted out in the open... usually exiles who have left their homes. These elves are usually Wind or Fire attribute. High Elf:
High Elves are the most commonly seen, and are the most likely to be seen living in cities. They tend to have cultures closer to those of the other city-dwellers they live with, but still often consider themselves superior... even if they're nicer about it. These elves are usually Water or Earth attribute. Wood Elf:
Though secluded, these elves tend to be among the easiest to get along with. They enjoy the wilderness, live simpler lives, and even the company of monsters. Though even less likely to be seen in a city than Dark Elves, some do decide to wander to enjoy nature or learn about the modern world. These elves are usually Earth attribute. Statblocks Humans are one of the most common races on Terra, and usually live within the many city-states dotting its landscape. Ungifted: Aside from a small handful of Magi, Humans cannot naturally use magic. They require some kind of external power to be able to do so, such as a magitech focus or an elemental patron. Elemental Variety: As some kind of weird cosmic joke, despite not having natural access to magic, humans are the most elemantally varied race on Terra. Humans can be born as any elemental affinity, including Light. Elemental Tribes: Many humans are born within one of the elemental tribes, which can be found with Fire, Water, Earth, Wind, and Shadow affinities. There are no Light elemental tribes. These humans form a pact with an elemental patron at a young age, and are gifted a portion of that elemental's power to enable the use of magic. In return, they promise to help maintain balance on Terra. Treat an Elemental Tribe human as if they were a natural spellcaster, limited to the element of their tribe. ]]></description><link>races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Races.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thank you for your interest in playtesting the Cendaran TTRPG! We're looking forward to seeing what sort of trouble you all get yourselves into. These rules will change regularly, but we'll make sure to mention any changes in the Discord!]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 21:53:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>